C. Jordan Ball III Tel: 757.425.6200 jordan@cjordanball.info https://cjordanball.info https://github.com/cjordanball

www.linkedin.com/in/cjordanball

Software / Web Developer

JavaScript | NodeJS | React | Angular2 | Postgres | MongoDB

PROFILE

Former attorney turned programmer/web developer, with experience designing and building full-stack web applications within the NodeJS / Express environment. Highly skilled as a problem solver, ranked 1st or 2nd out of 65,000+ users on the coderbyte.com coding challenge website. A lifelong learner who combines a love of new technologies with a passion for digging deep into programming fundamentals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS (most developed are bolded)

Programming/Markup Languages: JavaScript (ES6), C, Java, Go, HTML, CSS

Server-Side Frameworks: NodeJS, Express, Swagger

Front-End Frameworks: React/Redux, Angular4, Angular, Bootstrap

Database: MongoDB / Mongoose, PostgreSQL / Sequelize

Charting: d3, Highcharts
Testing: Mocha, Jasmine

Other: AWS (EC2, S3, Route53, IAM, etc.), Git/GitHub, Bitbucket, Heroku

Webpack, Docker, Digital Ocean, Pivotal Tracker, JIRA, agile develop-

ment

EXPERIENCE

Shockoe

Aug 2016 to May 2017

Software engineer creating web applications for large corporate clients. Lead development role in setting up application using Angular2 framework enabling national retailer to manage inventory through mobile devices used by employees connected to company database. Lead front-end developer for application allowing employees to make reservations on corporate buses and for managers to supervise bus movement and ridership.

Lumiary

May to July 2016

Contract position working as a developer for team updating front end of a customer data application currently employing a Backbone / Marionette framework. Creating new views to designer specifications as well as updating / debugging previously created views. Preparatory tasks to assist development of React / Redux app to replace current product.

CaseNEX

Aug 2015 to Feb 2016

Software developer on team designing and implementing major commercial web-based application for the education market. Responsible for programming throughout the development stack, including basic design and layout of app components, implementing components using JavaScript / React / Flux, setting up routes in a REST routing structure using Swagger, writing PostgreSQL database queries to react with application API, and distributing state application data as needed through a Flux event framework.

Web Developer

March 2015 to July 2015

Developing web apps, primarily using NodeJS, Angular, MongoDB, and the Ruby/Rails framework.



C. Jordan Ball III

Software / Web Developer

EDUCATION (Degree Programs)

Manhattan School of Music

New York City

Bachelor of Music—Classical Guitar

Georgetown University Law Center

Washington, DC

Juris Doctor

New York University School of Law

New York City

LL.M.—Taxation

EDUCATION (Other)

General Assembly

Seattle, WA

November 2014– February 2015

Web Development Immersive

Full-time immersive coding boot camp, building web apps using MEAN stack and Ruby/Rails framework. Devoted approximately 80 to 90+ hours per week, including class sessions, homework, and building full-scale web applications. Graduated with extensive experience in designing and building web apps from front-end design to server-side / database.

Harvard University/edX

Verified Certificate

CS50—Introduction to Computer Science

May 2015

Harvard's gateway computer science course. Although considered one of the most rigorous undergraduate courses at Harvard, it has proved so popular that in 2015 it was adopted by Yale as its introductory computer science course, via lectures streamed from the Harvard campus!

The first two-thirds of this twelve week course are implemented in C, followed by sections addressing the Internet, web applications, and computer security, utilizing PHP, JavaScript, SQL and other common web languages / frameworks. Graded assignments consist of nine problem sets plus a final project. Topics covered include: C syntax and programming structures; debugging techniques, particularly use of the gdb debugging tool; analysis and implementation of algorithms, with a focus on asymptotic run times of common searching and sorting methods; data structures, including arrays, trees, tries, hash tables, linked lists, queues, and stacks; memory allocation and management, including use of pointers, heap, and stack memory; and file input/output, both dynamically and at the command line.

Code Fellows Completed

Foundations II: JavaScript

October 2014

Survey of the fundamentals of JavaScript, including basics of functional, asynchronous programming, object-oriented JavaScript concepts, AJAX/JSON, use of libraries such as lodash, underscore, jQuery, use of Git/GitHub.

Online Courses

Udemy, egghead.io, Treehouse

AWS Certified Solutions Architect—Associate 2017 (in progress)
Docker for DevOps
Docker Technologies for DevOps and Developers
React Native with Redux (in progress)
Advanced React and Redux
Modern React with Redux
Build Web Apps with React and Flux
The Complete Developer's Guide to MongoDB
(continued)

C. Jordan Ball III

Software / Web Developer

EDUCATION (Other)

Online Courses (cont.)

Udemy, egghead.io, Treehouse

Complete Guide to Angular4 Learn and Understand Angular Unit Testing Angular Webpack2: The Complete Developer's Guide ES6 JavaScript: The Complete Developer's Guide

NodeJS Basics

Learn and Understand NodeJS

Build a Simple Dynamic Site with NodeJS

NodeJS Codeless API Creation: Up and Running with Swagger

Use D3 to Build Interactive Charts with JavaScript

Backbone Tutorial

Git Basics

HTML / HTML Tables / HTML Forms

CSS Basics

CSS - Beyond the Basics

Ruby Basics

Java Basics

AJAX Basics

NodeJS Basics

Understanding "this" in JavaScript